<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Hanzal, PhD</title>
    <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simon Hanzal, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://simonhanzal.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Teaching psychology at the University of Glasgow’s School of Psychology and Neuroscience. I have completed my PhD under Prof Monika Harvey, Prof Gregor Thut and Dr Gemma Learmonth.
My main research interest is the intersection between motivation and attention and their effects on performance. During my PhD, I contributed to research using electroencephalography (EEG) to detect biomarkers associated with mechanisms involved in fatigue. I also investigated the role of ageing in sustained attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/education/</guid>
      <description>PhD Psychology University of Glasgow, UK
September 2021 - September 2025
thesis: Investigating suitability of neurofeedback to improve fatigue
Visiting Scholar University of Western Ontario, Canada
June 2023 - July 2023
Collaborated and exchanged insights with colleagues, working with fNIRS data of vegetative state patients and beyond at the Owen lab within the Mind and Brain Institute.
MSc Research Methods of Psychological Science, distinction University of Glasgow, UK
September 2020 - August 2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>klaraluczkahanzalova.com since 2023
https://klaraluczkahanzalova.com
Author web of an emmerging creator.
simonhanzalfatigue.netlify.app 2023
https://simonhanzalfatigue.netlify.app/post/inverse_efficiency/
An interactive documentation website and visual aid for a conference.
EEG public engagement since 2022
https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2023.01.20.524682v1
EEG data colection for an exciting project bringing cognitive neuroscience research to the public.
simonhanzal.github.io since 2022
https://simonhanzal.github.io
My own small part of the internet.
SART online 2021
https://simonhanzal.github.io/prototype/task.html
Published paper on a custom large online behavioural experiment I implemented online during Covid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Past Papers Hanzal, S., Learmonth, G., Thut, G., &amp;amp; Harvey, M. (2024). Probing sustained attention and fatigue across the lifespan. PloS One, 19(7), e0292695. doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0292695
Hanzal, S., Learmonth, G., Thut, G., &amp;amp; Harvey, M. (2023). Neural correlates of inducing fatigue with a sustained attention task. Journal of Vision (Charlottesville, Va.), 23(9), 4923. https://doi.org/10.1167/jov.23.9.4923
Turner, C., Baylan, S., Bracco, M., Cruz, G., Hanzal, S., Keime, M., Kuye, I., McNeill, D., Ng, Z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/skills/</guid>
      <description>Coding I have multiple years of experience accessing data, including data from databases using MySQL and SQLite as well as restructuring and cleaning data using Numpy, Pandas and Scipy in Python and the amazing Tidyverse in R, often as part of larger projects organised through Jupyter notebooks or R Packages.
In the following code, I use a combination of base R and Tidyverse functional programming to make a useful fuction to carry out an operation that often occurs in wrangling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
