<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Hanzal</title>
    <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simon Hanzal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://simonhanzal.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a passionate and experienced postgraduate researcher at the University of Glasgow’s School of Psychology and Neuroscience. I work with Prof Monika Harvey, Prof Gregor Thut and Dr Gemma Learmonth.
My main topic of interest is motivation and changes in attention and their role in the experience of fatigue. I contributed to research on the role of alerting mechanisms in ageing and stroke rehabilitation using electroencephalography (EEG) as well as development of clinical behavioural testing using online experimentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/education/</guid>
      <description>Visiting Scholar University of Western Ontario, Canada
June 2023 - July 2023
I collaborated and exchanged insight with colleagues at the Owen lab within the Mind and Brain Institute.
Postgraduate Research Degree, Psychology University of Glasgow, UK
September 2021 - now
thesis: Investigating suitability of neurofeedback to improve fatigue
MSc Research Methods of Psychological Science, distinction University of Glasgow, UK
September 2020 - August 2021
dissertation: Measuring attention in the general population: an online study</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>klaraluczkahanzalova.com since 2023
https://klaraluczkanzalova.com
Author web of an emmerging creator.
simonhanzalfatigue.netlify.app 2023
https://simonhanzalfatigue.netlify.app/post/inverse_efficiency/
An interactive documentation website and visual aid for a conference.
EEG public engagement since 2022
https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2023.01.20.524682v1
EEG data colection for an exciting project bringing cognitive neuroscience research to the public.
simonhanzal.github.io since 2022
https://simonhanzal.github.io
My own small part of the internet.
SART online 2021
https://simonhanzal.github.io/prototype/task.html
Published paper on a custom large online behavioural experiment I implemented online during Covid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Current Research: How does a psychological experiment work? Disentangling the individual components of our mind that make our performance. I am currently running an experiment integrating insight into attention, cognition, volition and all the processes that govern our behavioural. If you are interested in taking part, contact me!
Past Papers Hanzal, S., Learmonth, G., Thut, G., &amp;amp; Harvey, M. (2024). Probing sustained attention and fatigue across the lifespan. PloS One, 19(7), e0292695.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/skills/</guid>
      <description>Coding I have multiple years of experience accessing data, including data from databases using MySQL and SQLite as well as restructuring and cleaning data using Numpy, Pandas and Scipy in Python and the amazing Tidyverse in R, often as part of larger projects organised through Jupyter notebooks or R Packages.
In the following code, I use a combination of base R and Tidyverse functional programming to make a useful fuction to carry out an operation that often occurs in wrangling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
