<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Simon Hanzal</title>
        <link>localhost/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Simon Hanzal</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="localhost/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Psychology of Free Will</title>
            <link>localhost/posts/freewill/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>localhost/posts/freewill/</guid>
            <description>„But it is clear that ethics has nothing to do with punishment and reward in the ordinary sense. This question as to the consequences of an action must therefore be irrelevant. At least these consequences will not be events. For there must be something right in that formulation of the question. There must be some sort of ethical reward and ethical punishment, but this must lie in the action itself. Of the will as the subject of the ethical we cannot speak.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>„But it is clear that ethics has nothing to do with punishment and reward in the ordinary sense. This question as to the consequences of an action must therefore be irrelevant. At least these consequences will not be events. For there must be something right in that formulation of the question. There must be some sort of ethical reward and ethical punishment, but this must lie in the action itself. Of the will as the subject of the ethical we cannot speak. And the will as a phenomenon is only of interest to psychology.“ - Ludwig Wittgenstein, Tractatus p. 6.422 – 6.423</p>
<p>The groundwork of contemporary psychology is the experiment. It enables the isolation and reproduction of specific behaviours in a hand-picked sample, thought to represent the whole human population. Yet, the goal of psychology is to give account of event-unspecific, highly abstract inner functions of the mind. Wittgenstein mentions one of these: free will, necessary for ethical judgement.</p>
<p>Some impressive research exists (Haynes et al., 2008, Herrmann et al., 2008, Soon, Bode &amp; Haynesa, 2013), where concrete neural signals have been successfully identified to serve as markers of an unconsciously present inclination to action. These signals to some degree determine that a free action will take place even prior to conscious awareness of the intention to act. These Bereitscheiftspotentiale (preparedness potentials) uncovered in the work of the German psychologist Libet using the millisecond-precise electroencephalograph (EEG) (Libet et al., 1983) preclude perception of intention to act even in the magnitude of seconds, providing a viable research avenue for aspiring determinists till this day (Braun, Wessler &amp; Friese, 2021).</p>
<p><img src="/free_will.png" alt="Free will"></p>
<p>Perhaps more interestingly, similar signals popped up in my own line of work, investigating a different phenomenon, but using the same technology – EEG. As it seems, the decision to press or not to press a button on a computer is at first perceived as fairly voluntary and firmly under the control of the undertaker. However, my participants were still prone to err and experience awareness of their mistake just before making it, but too late to cancel their action. Despite having four seconds to decide whether to press a button, hardly anyone waited longer than a second. The task was rigged from the beginning, anticipating that bored participants automate their responses and experience attentional lapses as a result. Because of the automation, it is then too hard to abort a response even when attention gives a red light about an impeding mistake.</p>
<p>None of this is shocking. What is shocking is that the signal that came out of their heads prior to their button press, and even prior to their awareness of their own intent to press, helps to determine whether they were about to make a mistake. This signal was unknown to them but known to the researcher. With high enough precision, it is possible to “read the mind” ahead of time and predict their decision. To extrapolate a little: in a world where the company Neuralink plans to implant microchips in people’s heads, it is conceivable to measure the signal so precisely that we would really have access to information enabling the prediction of people’s actions.</p>
<p>Naïve proponents of free will often employ the readily available example of being able to spontaneously move one’s finger. Surely, I have free will if I can move whenever I please. But if a subconscious neural convulsion is present even prior to my spontaneous decision to move, am I just under an illusion of that freedom? The most common-sense intuition about free will is in trouble.</p>
<p>The examples provided show that scientists do get some results if they average highly sterile trials carefully fashioned to be alike and where all subjects constrain their behaviour to align with a carefully managed research aim. In these cases, we must accept that will-as-a-phenomenon is partly explained away. On the contrary, we can abide by Wittgenstein’s distinction and challenge the determinist story as based on constrained laboratory environment which cannot contribute anything at all to knowledge of free will. Instead, it produces but parodic doxa: shadows which occasionally correlate, sometimes by accident, with the true underlying mental faculty of free will. What tragedy if a shadow were mistaken for reality and were treated so. An ethical decision stripped of its freedom becomes explainable, and so, conditional. To propose an argument for free will, I will start with Elisabeth Anscombe’s thought exercise (Anscombe, 1957): When driving my car, I see a person walking over the street. I firmly press on the pedal and run the person over. “Why” did I run the person over? Because I had a subconscious inkling seen in my Bereitshaftspotential 500ms prior, which then moved me to decide to operate my motor cortex and so bring my leg into motion, pressing the pedal. It is comparable to an act in a laboratory when one spontaneously presses a button or moves a finger. In a social setting, or at court, such answer is not only insufficient; it is asocial mockery.</p>
<p>One more example, consider this scene where Meursault shoots an Arab in The Stranger: A shaft of light shot upward from the steel, and I felt as if a long, thin blade transfixed my forehead. At the same moment all the sweat that had accumulated in my eyebrows splashed down on my eyelids, covering them with a warm film of moisture. Beneath a veil of brine and tears my eyes were blinded; I was conscious only of the cymbals of the sun clashing on my skull, and, less distinctly, of the keen blade of light flashing up from the knife, scarring my eyelashes, and gouging into my eyeballs. Then everything began to reel before my eyes, a fiery gust came from the sea, while the sky cracked in two, from end to end, and a great sheet of flame poured down through the rift. Every nerve in my body was a steel spring, and my grip closed on the revolver. The trigger gave, and the smooth underbelly of the butt jogged my palm (McCarthy, 2004).</p>
<p>No. I run the person over (conclusion), because I hated him (premise 1), and revenge is best served cold (premise 2). Such an explanation exhausts the “why” question. Pure description of any event forming the execution of that well-deliberated judgement, even if highly intricate, fails to do so. Likewise, a participant in a Bereitshaftspotential experiment is really just acting out one ethical judgment: to take part in an experiment and comply. So was the case for my participants. What I can tell from qualitative data, their intention was mostly to help me, with a bonus of earning £13. This is why they pressed the button and this is why their central beta oscillatory power subconsciously increased, prior to a button press.</p>
<p>And so, the main mistake a determinist makes is that they confuse one average of explanatively insufficient behaviours with one case of explanatively satisfactory behaviour, which turns out to be always experimentally unmeasurable.</p>
<p>Just for the sake of professionality, I would like to address at least one objection to the argument, but I encourage you to consider more should you wish to defend free will. A prospective gap in this reasoning is that several intentions or higher-order explanations at once are possible for the fact at hand. I may not only be enacting vengeance, I could also be in a great rush to the airport. To answer the objection, the principle of sufficient reason can be invoked: intentions are combined, some diminishing and some increasing the chance for me to decide one way or another. One final explanation may not exhaust the entirety of my reasoning at the time, but it is sufficient to give a consistent meaning to the act. Running someone over as a planned act of vengeance is more sufficient as an explanation than negligence in travel to the airport, especially in light of any further unmentioned but likely evidence.</p>
<p>So, how can empirical psychologists study free will? Using experiments, not very much. Not without getting into trouble with ethics committees as our predecessors did (Milgram, 1963). Yet, resignation on the experimental method and retained insistence on scientific basis of psychological research may lead psychologists down a path of self-promotion under the guise of scientist, using the décor of science, without using its principles (Cremer, 2023).
Better to keep the experimental method, but then admit that whereof one cannot speak, thereof one must be silent. Alternatively, let us admit that psychology as empirical science is always guided by psychology as a philosophical study of a human person. Otherwise, we’d have to try and sell the relevance of a highly unsatisfactory field of neurobehavioural studies, where we discuss modest correlations between specific isolated moments of laboratory sessions of mostly twenty-something psychology students sitting in silence to press buttons now and then and where barely detectable increases and decreases in brain activity in some of them explain some of that button clicking.</p>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<ol>
<li>Anscombe, G. E. M. (1957). intention. Blackwell.</li>
<li>Braun, M. N., Wessler, J., &amp; Friese, M. (2021). A meta-analysis of libet-style experiments. Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews, 128, 182-198. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2021.06.018">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2021.06.018</a> Cremer, T. (2023;2021;). A religious vaccination? how christian communities react to right-wing populism in germany, france and the US. Government and Opposition (London), 58(1), 162-182. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/gov.2021.18">https://doi.org/10.1017/gov.2021.18</a></li>
<li>Haynes, J., Soon, C. S., Brass, M., &amp; Heinze, H. (2008). Unconscious determinants of free decisions in the human brain. Nature Neuroscience, 11(5), 543-545. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2112">https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2112</a></li>
<li>Herrmann, C. S., Pauen, M., Min, B., Busch, N. A., &amp; Rieger, J. W. (2008;2007;). Analysis of a choice-reaction task yields a new interpretation of libet’s experiments. International Journal of Psychophysiology, 67(2), 151-157. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2007.10.013">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2007.10.013</a></li>
<li>Libet, B., Gleason, C. A., Wright, E. W., &amp; Pearl, D. K. (1983). Time of conscious intention to act in relation to onset of cerebral activity (readiness-potential). The unconscious initiation of a freely voluntary act. Brain : a journal of neurology, 106 (Pt 3), 623–642. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/106.3.623">https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/106.3.623</a> McCarthy, P., &amp; ProQuest (Firm). (2004). Albert Camus, the Stranger (2nd ed.). Cambridge University Press.</li>
<li>Milgram, S. (1963). behavioral study of obedience. Journal of Abnormal Psychology (1965), 67, 371. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0040525">https://doi.org/10.1037/h0040525</a></li>
<li>Soon, C. S., HE, A. H., Bode, S., &amp; Haynesa, J. (2013). Predicting free choices for abstract intentions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences - PNAS, 110(15), 6217-6222. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1212218110">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1212218110</a></li>
<li>Wittgenstein, L., Pears, D. F., McGuinness, B., &amp; Russell, B. (2014). Tractatus logico-philosophicus. Routledge. <a href="https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315884950">https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315884950</a></li>
</ol>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Humans and monkeys are different?</title>
            <link>localhost/posts/humansapes/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>localhost/posts/humansapes/</guid>
            <description>I present to you the findings which show that we can recognise objects both as literal things and symbols, whereas animals treat all objects in the world literally. It is evidence based on empirical observation of the world and which is thus factual for believers and non-believers alike. It is an outcome of an impressive work of science spanning several continents and nearly a thousand of humans and animals, published this April in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of France, doi.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I present to you the findings which show that we can recognise objects both as literal things and symbols, whereas animals treat all objects in the world literally. It is evidence based on empirical observation of the world and which is thus factual for believers and non-believers alike. It is an outcome of an impressive work of science spanning several continents and nearly a thousand of humans and animals, published this April in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of France, doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2023123118.</p>
<p>The basis of the paper boils down to a simple idea. Geometric shapes can be broken down into abstract elements – right angles, parallel lines and symmetry. Only humans have the ability to grasp and utilise the immaterial idea of these elements. We subdivide any geometric shape into these more abstracts concepts without even realising. This is analogous in words, numbers and music notes. There is no need to go into more detail over the intricacies and arguments about this conception. The relevant point for the study is that humans do not learn lists of right angles (or any other symbol) by heart. Once we understand one, we can abstract it from any perceived shape and use it as a concept to understand the world. Animals can be taught really well to recognise particular objects by being rewarded with food. They can learn a list of squares or hinges by heart, but only as signs for incoming food. In this respect, a square does not mean anything geometric or symmetric. It is just a visually specific shorthand for food with no further sub-features.</p>
<p>The researchers behind this paper worked with baboon monkeys, who are believed to have one of the most similar visual systems to humans. They taught them to identify geometric quadrilaterals (four-sided) such as rectangles, parallelograms and trapezoids and to tell them apart from other irregular polygons. They were taught that these shapes, being the odd ones out, are a sign for a reward in the form of food. Once the researchers were sure that the baboons were able to identify the various geometric shapes and understood the task of finding the odd one out, they experimentally compared them on the full shape recognition task with humans.</p>
<p><img src="/human_ape.png" alt="A human and an ape not being similar"></p>
<p>Both humans and baboons saw a collection of scattered geometric shapes. They were meant to indicate whether they saw a shape that did not fit into the collection. For instance, a collection of right kites with one lacking a right angle. The wrong shape was always geometrically irregular. An animal was then rewarded with food for a successful identification of an irregular shape. To clarify, this meant that a monkey would identify a wrong shape among those it had already been exposed to in its training. The difference from their original learning sessions was focus on all the used types of quadrilaterals simultaneously, not just one at time. The task was the same for humans, just without a reward. They were also just meant to indicate the wrong shape. Importantly, the researchers manipulated the presence of underlying geometric features by utilising eleven different quadrilaterals ranging from the most regular like squares to those almost irregular like iso-trapezoids. They then went to see whether geometric regularity of the shape predicted performance.</p>
<p>The results were unanimously convincing. The human ability to see geometric patterns was directly related to shape complexity. The more irregular the shape, the worse was the human performance. The monkey’s ability to find any one shape improved over time due to learning to pair correct answers with food but turned out to be the same for any shape no matter its complexity. A square and an iso-trapesoid posed the same challenge. This means that the animals could not abstract any geometric elements from the shapes. They did not use any geometric principles when trying to find the shapes, they just relied on memory of older instances of the same shapes without making any abstraction or connection between them. The humans on the other hand saw the shapes as a collection of geometric features they abstracted to solve the task more effectively for geometrically regular shapes. This way, humans demonstrated their ability to draw on abstraction of geometric rules to tell the shapes apart more effectively.</p>
<p>An objection can arise that the analysis was too linear. Therefore, the authors provided a secondary analysis using machine learning modelling. They tried predicting the behaviour by two artificial intelligence models. One assumed that each shape has a certain amount of regular geometric properties and predicted behaviour based on a simulated brain encoding geometric rules when deciding about the odd shape out. The other model only treated the shape as a collection of dots that was processed in cortical layers from bottom up and was adapted from previous visual perception research. The first model predicted human behaviour. The second was successful with the monkeys.</p>
<p>A common objection to the conclusions can be found in the carpeted world hypothesis. It says that humans are primed since birth to detect right angles, parallel lines and symmetry. We are merely habituated to them instead of having to construct any immaterial abstractions. However, this was addressed as the researchers also used a cohort of people from the Himba tribe which is one of the few still completely pre-industrial societies. Their living environment contains very little geometric regularity. Even these people who had no exposure to mathematical education behaved in a very similar manner to French adults and another control cohort, preschool children. On the other hand, the monkeys used for these experiments were tested and kept in proximity to facilities built in an industrial fashion. These included plenty of right angles and parallel lines in much greater abundance than a Himba village. It becomes quite apparent that the objection cannot hold.</p>
<p>There is another objection about making two fake categories of symbolic and non-symbolic thought. This objection can be supported by the claim that there was a degradation in this effect of complexity of the geometric shape on success in humans. It was true that the children were not affected by complexity as much as the adults and the performance of the Himba people was even poorer than that of the children, seemingly approaching the monkeys. But there was still a massive leap between the abilities of the tribesmen and the smartest of the monkeys. Some would then make the case that it would have been interesting to see whether this degradation continued beyond the baboons, but that would be missing the point of how massive and nonlinear the human-animal leap was. A degradation relative to the baboons would be relevant only for the animal kingdom and purely indicate anatomic deficiency in the visual processing system of the brain, but the principle of difference in symbolic thought would remain.</p>
<p>The outcomes of this experiment are twofold. On the one hand, it provides some powerful and strong evidence which can be kept at the back of one’s mind when discussing the issue of human uniqueness. But it also points to a deeper philosophical reality. Atop of the abilities of animals, our existence is characterised by the ability to understand and reason using immaterial truths. Reversing the sentence, immaterial truths make us human.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The forced loneliness of coronavirus lockdowns (from the GIST)</title>
            <link>localhost/posts/coronavirus/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>localhost/posts/coronavirus/</guid>
            <description>What is forced loneliness? Abandonment is nasty and that’s why isolation makes for a terrific horror plot. Few tropes drive fearsome suspense more than extended isolation in a log cabin situated in the mountains or being trapped on a spaceship. The isolated characters in The Shining, The Thing and at the end of the classic The Blair Witch Project are pretty much in psychological pain even before physical pain arrives.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/loneliness.webp" alt="loneliness"></p>
<h2 id="what-is-forced-loneliness">What is forced loneliness?</h2>
<p>Abandonment is nasty and that’s why isolation makes for a terrific horror plot. Few tropes drive fearsome suspense more than extended isolation in a log cabin situated in the mountains or being trapped on a spaceship. The isolated characters in <em>The Shining</em>, <em>The Thing</em> and at the end of the classic <em>The Blair Witch Project</em> are pretty much in psychological pain even before physical pain arrives. Moreover, isolation is used in real life for punishment in the form of solitary confinement1. COVID-19 has changed our perspective on isolation. It’s now deemed important for the individual, as well as societies around the world, to undergo a lockdown to protect public health. However, seeing that isolation is there to terrify, both figuratively in movies and literally in correctional facilities, this measure comes at a price.</p>
<p>Yet, we have only a few clues to give us the price estimate.There are a couple of notable studies looking at the recent epidemics of MERS in South Korea2 and the Arab Peninsula3. Research suggests that people experiencing social isolation showed higher stress and anxiety, craving of company and desire to socially reconnect. Some quarantined hospital staff and self-isolating people even showed signs of post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD)4. Some more explorative work concluded that individuals experienced estrangement from others and stigmatisation. A few reported that they were perceived as “impure” (by themselves or others) or were thought to still be infected even long after their illness was gone.</p>
<p>There are several neuroscientific studies which identify key brain areas involved in these experiences. Some of the areas are responsible for emotional responses to other people or the desire to connect with them. Others for carrying out basic movements and avoidance of dangerous places. The studies show that these complex functions often require the coordinated action of an automated social brain pathway, along with a rational pathway to “think through decisions”. The latest research suggests that a disbalance between the two is at the core of the resulting health risks. These include increased stress levels and inflammation resulting in lower immune system strength, tissue and blood vessel damage, and disruption to relationships.</p>
<p>Other researchers track changes in blood flow through the brain using a method called functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI). They found that a part of the parietal cortex5 (found on the sides of the brain) processes both the social and actual distance from other people at the same time, and this may make it difficult to distinguish between social and physical spaces.  If the perception of physical distance from others leads to the perception of social distance, it means that social distancing can automatically make people become distant and removed from others. In turn, social isolation in times of epidemics can produce “forced loneliness”.</p>
<p>Forced loneliness may lead to lower empathy. Drawing on famous research by Eisenberger6, researchers showed that pain induced by social isolation leads to indifference to people around us. Their work complements the feelings of mistrust in social interactions perceived by those who had to distance themselves during a recent MERS outbreak7. Furthermore, those perceived and treated as dangerous (like COVID-infected people) may respond by showing avoidant and outwardly unpleasant behaviour. As a result, people are less keen to help them. This shows that epidemics leave infected people feeling stigmatised and abandoned, potentially leading into a spiralling pattern of isolation, appearing hostile and ending up even more isolated.</p>
<p>Yet, psychology also tells us that most vulnerabilities can have a silver lining. One study looked at the impact of perceived loneliness on significant relationships through measuring their hormonal levels. The findings suggest that we’ll begin to actively seek those closest to us to cope with adversity. Whilst complete lack of social contact is likely to lead to more stress, a healthy dose of solitude can help us rediscover how precious and important some of our nearest truly are.</p>
<h2 id="three-risks-and-how-to-avoid-them">Three risks and how to avoid them</h2>
<p>So, what are the main signs that we are beginning to suffer from lockdown loneliness? Recent studies indicate three main risk areas and ways to mitigate them.</p>
<p>A decrease in empathy can result in long-term reduction in quality of relationships. However, the presence of family members and partners could partly reverse the disbalance that social isolation causes in our two neural networks.</p>
<p>Isolation can lead to oversensitivity to stress and rumination on risks to health and other threats. We can become overly sensitive to any upsetting social situation. Such stress can lead to inflammation of the immune system and reduced ability to resist infection. It can even slow down our generation of new brain cells. Simply put, we don’t want that. To stay healthy, it can be helpful to remember that we are all in a lockdown situation. We can try to accept that it’s normal for those under lockdown to have a worse time socialising. In many ways, all people in lockdown are in the same boat. Perhaps acknowledging this shared social vulnerability caused  by the lockdown can be a way to reconnect more effectively.</p>
<p>Decision-making may also change due to social disbalance. The aforementioned parietal cortex is also responsible for assessing risk and can issue commands to adjust to that risk. Our natural social contact craving mechanisms may further disbalance decision-making, and people may struggle to estimate the risks of social contact during an epidemic.</p>
<p>Poor decision-making may also lead to an increase in displays of public aggression wherever frustration from a long lockdown builds up. This should again lead to self-reflection. We should remember not to act too impulsively and allow ourselves extra time, even just an extra five seconds, to think through a decision. Although this may seem like a brief moment, it can be a huge investment into our mental health in the long-term.</p>
<p>Although social distancing can help to decrease risks to physical health, we must not forget mental health. Socialising and seeing other people outside of the context of living spaces is an absolutely necessary aspect of human life. On the one hand, we are trying to remain in control of the situation and fulfil basic physical needs. However, due to a lack of empathy, feelings of distance and worse social decision-making, we can grow distant from each other and end up with poorer health overall.</p>
<p>Perhaps paradoxically, a measure which has undoubtedly protected health can also make it more vulnerable as a side effect. As the current global pandemic unfolds, we can expect to see not only short-term adverse effects on public health but also long-term psychological costs which carry with themselves a dear mental health bill. These prospects themselves could make for a horror plot.</p>
<p><em>This article was specialist edited by Katrina Wesencraft and copy-edited by Kirstin Leslie.</em></p>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="https:www.psychologytoday.com/intl/blog/brain-chemistry/201902/the-effects-solitary-confinement-the-brain">https:www.psychologytoday.com/intl/blog/brain-chemistry/201902/the-effects-solitary-confinement-the-brain</a></li>
<li><a href="https:www.who.int/westernpacific/emergencies/2015-mers-outbreak">https:www.who.int/westernpacific/emergencies/2015-mers-outbreak</a></li>
<li><a href="https:ww.cdc.gov/coronavirus/mers/index.html">https:ww.cdc.gov/coronavirus/mers/index.html</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/post-traumatic-stress-disorder/symptoms-causes/syc-20355967">https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/post-traumatic-stress-disorder/symptoms-causes/syc-20355967</a></li>
<li><a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0004360">https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0004360</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.edge.org/conversation/naomi_eisenberger-why-rejection-hurts">https://www.edge.org/conversation/naomi_eisenberger-why-rejection-hurts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5177805/">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5177805/</a></li>
</ol>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
