<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>psychology on Simon Hanzal</title>
    <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in psychology on Simon Hanzal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simonhanzal.github.io/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Psychology of Free Will</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/posts/freewill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/posts/freewill/</guid>
      <description>„But it is clear that ethics has nothing to do with punishment and reward in the ordinary sense. This question as to the consequences of an action must therefore be irrelevant. At least these consequences will not be events. For there must be something right in that formulation of the question. There must be some sort of ethical reward and ethical punishment, but this must lie in the action itself. Of the will as the subject of the ethical we cannot speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humans and monkeys are different?</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/posts/humansapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/posts/humansapes/</guid>
      <description>I present to you the findings which show that we can recognise objects both as literal things and symbols, whereas animals treat all objects in the world literally. It is evidence based on empirical observation of the world and which is thus factual for believers and non-believers alike. It is an outcome of an impressive work of science spanning several continents and nearly a thousand of humans and animals, published this April in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of France, doi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The forced loneliness of coronavirus lockdowns (from the GIST)</title>
      <link>https://simonhanzal.github.io/posts/coronavirus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhanzal.github.io/posts/coronavirus/</guid>
      <description>What is forced loneliness? Abandonment is nasty and that’s why isolation makes for a terrific horror plot. Few tropes drive fearsome suspense more than extended isolation in a log cabin situated in the mountains or being trapped on a spaceship. The isolated characters in The Shining, The Thing and at the end of the classic The Blair Witch Project are pretty much in psychological pain even before physical pain arrives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
